<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.9.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2022-06-23T21:58:22+03:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Kutay’s Amazing Blog</title><subtitle>An amazing blog for anything that I write and more.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Turkish Literature Article Reading and Summarizing</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/Turkish-Literature-Reading-and-Summarizing/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Turkish Literature Article Reading and Summarizing" /><published>2022-05-23T20:32:48+03:00</published><updated>2022-05-23T20:32:48+03:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/Turkish-Literature-Reading-and-Summarizing</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/Turkish-Literature-Reading-and-Summarizing/">&lt;p&gt;İslam Ansiklopedisi - Beş Şehir&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bu kısa makalede Beş Şehir eserinin konusu ve anlattıkları bahsedilmiştir. 
Tanpınar’dan bahsederek giriş yapılmış, devamında beş şehirden bahsedilmiştir bu bölümlerde karşılaşan şeylerden de bahsedilmiştir. 
Bunun yanında eserin türü üzerine durulmuştur, hangi türe girdiği tartışılmıştır. 
En sonda ise &lt;em&gt;Beş Şehir’in, şiir üslûbu ağır basan, deneme-monografi karışımı bir tür olarak kabul edilmesi daha yerinde olur.&lt;/em&gt; diyerek tartışmayı sonlandırmıştır.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ahmet Hamdi Tanpınar - Beş Şehir&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bu yazı diğerine göre daha uzundur ve daha detaylıdır. 
Yazıya Tanpınar’ın hayatı anlatılarak giriş yapılmıştır ve Tanpınar’ın eserlerinde kimlerden esinlendiği de bahsedilmiştir. 
Tanpınar’ın sanat hayatı ve sanat anlayışı da bahsedilmiştir. Sonrasında genel hatları ile yazdığı yazılar ve eserlerden bahsedilmiştir.
Beş Şehir’den bahsetmeden önce deneme türü hakkında bilgi verilmiş ve Türk Edebiyatındaki yazarlardan bahsedilmiştir. 
Bunun devamında Beş Şehir’i kısaca incelemiş ve özetlemiştir. Analiz, beş farklı bölüme bölünmüştür, her bir şehir için ayrı bir bölüm şeklinde. 
Her bir şehri anlatırken o şehirdeki mimari, edebiyat ve türkülerden kısaca bahsedilmiştir. 
Yazının sonu da şöyle bitmektedir: &lt;em&gt;O topyekûn bir milletin farkında olmadan yitirdiği ve yerine yenisi de tam koyamadığı medeniyet yiğitini şehir şehir aramıştır.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;İslam Ansiklopedisi - Tanpınar&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bu yazıda Tanpınar’ın hayatı ve sanat anlayışından bahsedilmiştir. Konulara olan düşünceleri, hangi yazarlara benzerlik gösterdiği gibi şeylerden bahsedilmiştir. Yazının devamında Tanpınar’ın eserlerinden bahsedilmiştir.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="turkish" /><category term="article" /><category term="literature" /><summary type="html">İslam Ansiklopedisi - Beş Şehir</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Paved With Good Intentions: The 11th Hour</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/Paved_With-Good-Intentions-the-11th-Hour/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Paved With Good Intentions: The 11th Hour" /><published>2022-04-30T20:32:48+03:00</published><updated>2022-04-30T20:32:48+03:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/Paved_With-Good-Intentions-the-11th-Hour</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/Paved_With-Good-Intentions-the-11th-Hour/">&lt;p&gt;Climate change is an issue that has been very important for the last two decades. People have started to worry about what is going to happen to the world and humans if we continue this usage of materials and energy. To learn what happened and to have new perspectives, people are watching documentaries and films about global warming and climate change. A film/documentary made in 2007 is now one of the most searched films about climate change as the film has Leonardo DiCaprio as a narrator and co-producer. The film’s intention was to raise awareness and give out a message. The film did what its intention was, but it was very light and it didn’t motivate people to take action.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The 11th Hour&lt;/em&gt;, narrated and co-produced by Leonardo DiCaprio, gathers a group of nearly 50 respected experts to speak from their areas of knowledge about how we are despoiling our planet and what we might possibly do to turn things around. From the title, it can be understood that it sounds like a warning and that we don’t have much time left. Even in the film, it says that the time is 11:59:59 and that we have to take action. Then, why is this film wasting the viewers’ time as the film is 1 hour and 30 minutes long? This film can be squeezed into 30 minutes of information. Also, the information given in the film is mostly known by everyone. The film should have given more information and examples of how people can help the environment instead of explaining what climate change is and what it’s doing to the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The architects in the film show how we may construct “green” structures that use solar energy, eat their own waste, and act similarly to trees. There is no reason why every home (certainly every newly constructed one) would not have solar panels on the roof to help heat, light, and cool itself. Actually, there is just one reason: the energy companies would resist any attempt to reroute their massive subsidies toward eco-friendly homes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The film’s production was not great either. The 50 or so experts intercut and just talk and talk. Even Leonardo DiCaprio sounds like he’s presenting a school project to a class. They are all depicted as talking heads, so we hear them talk. Then we get some nature footage that was taken by a helicopter or something, and we see them talk more, until finally we’re thinking, enough already; I get it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some of the issues raised in The 11th Hour are common knowledge; there was no new information on climate change or global warming. It would be acceptable if the film inspired us to take action and accomplish things, but it does neither. The production was also subpar, with mostly dull nature photos and videos. “A bore,” Meyer the hairy economist once informed private investigator Travis McGee, “is anyone who deprives you of solitude without providing you with companionship.” Despite its great intentions, this film is boring.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="english" /><category term="the" /><category term="11th" /><category term="hour" /><category term="movie" /><category term="analysis" /><summary type="html">Climate change is an issue that has been very important for the last two decades. People have started to worry about what is going to happen to the world and humans if we continue this usage of materials and energy. To learn what happened and to have new perspectives, people are watching documentaries and films about global warming and climate change. A film/documentary made in 2007 is now one of the most searched films about climate change as the film has Leonardo DiCaprio as a narrator and co-producer. The film’s intention was to raise awareness and give out a message. The film did what its intention was, but it was very light and it didn’t motivate people to take action.</summary></entry></feed>